you
What's going on here?
for the powder room, and that's the last I see you.
Now, really, Harry?
Harry was the other guy.
I'm Sid.
Sid Arbuck.
You like me, remember?
Mr. Gold Rifery!
I protest!
Oh, darling, I am sorry, but I lost my key.
But that was two weeks ago.
You cannot go on or keep ringing my bell.
You disturb me.
You must have a key made.
But it won't do any good.
I just lose them all.
Come on, baby.
You like me.
You know you do.
I worship you, Mr. Auerbach, but good night, Mr. Auerbach.
Wait a minute.
What is this?
You like me.
I'm a liked guy.
You like me, baby.
You know you do.
Didn't I pick up the check for five people?
Your friends?
I never seen them before.
And when you ask for a little change for the powder room, what do I give you?
A $50 bill.
Now, doesn't that give me some rights?
In 30 seconds, I got to call the police.
All the time a disturbance.
I can't no sleep.
I got to get to my rest.
I'm an artist.
Or I got to call the vice squad on you.
Don't be angry, you dear little man.
I won't do it again.
If you promise not to be angry, I might let you take those pictures we mentioned.
When?
Sometime.
Anytime.
Good night.
Sorry to bother you, but I couldn't get the downstairs door open.
I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
I couldn't get the downstairs door open.
I said, I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
I'm sorry to wake you.
It's quite all right.
Could happen to anyone, quite frequently does, couldn't it?
I hate to...
I hate to bother you, but if I could ask one more favor, could I use the phone?
Sure.
Why not?
Thank you.
Well, this is a nice little place you've got here.
You just moved in too, huh?
No.
I've been here about a year.
The phone's over there.
Well, it was.
Oh, I remember.
I stuck it in the suitcase.
Kind of muffles the sound.
I'm sorry.
Is he all right?
Sure.
Sure he's okay, aren't you, cat?
Poor old cat.
Poor slob.
Poor slob without a name.
The way I look at it, I don't have the right to give him one.
We don't belong to each other.
We just took up by the river one day.
I don't even want to own anything until I can find a place where me and things go together.
I'm not sure where that is, but I know what it's like.
It's like Tiffany's.
Tiffany's?
You mean the jewelry store?
That's right.
I'm crazy about Tiffany's.
Listen.
You know those days when you get the mean reds?
The mean reds?
You mean like the blues?
No.
The blues are because you're getting fat or maybe it's been raining too long.
You're just sad, that's all.
The mean reds are horrible.
Suddenly you're afraid and you don't know what you're afraid of.
Did you ever get that feeling?
Sure.
When I get it, the only thing that does any good is to jump into a cab and go to Tiffany's.
It calms me down right away.
The quietness and the proud look of it.
Nothing very bad could happen to you there.
If I could find a real life place that made me feel like Tiffany's, then I'd buy some furniture and give the cat a name.
I'm sorry you wanted something.
Oh, the telephone.
It's just that I was supposed to meet somebody.
I mean, this is 10 o'clock Thursday morning, isn't it?
I just got off a plane from Rome, and I'm not too sure.
Thursday?
Is this Thursday?
I think so.
Thursday?
It's too gruesome.
Well, what's so gruesome about Thursday?
Nothing except I can never remember when it's coming up.
Wednesdays I generally just don't go to bed at all because I have to be up to catch the 10.45.
And they're so particular about visiting hours.
Would you be a darling to look under the bed and see if you can find a pair of alligator shoes?
Sure.
I've got to do something about the way I look.
I mean, a girl just can't go to Sing Sing with a green face.
Sing Sing?
Yes, I always thought it was a ridiculous name for a prison.
Sing Sing, I mean.
Sounds more like it should be an opera house or something.
Black Alligator.
You know, all the visitors make an effort to look their best.
It's only fair.
Actually, it's very touching, all the women wearing their prettiest things.
I just love them for it.
And I love the kids, too.
I mean, the kids the wives bring.
It should be sad seeing kids there, but it isn't.
They all have ribbons in their hair and lots of shine on their shoes.
You'd think there was going to be ice cream.
Now, as I understand it, what we're doing is getting you ready to visit somebody at Sing Sing.
That's right.
You can always tell what kind of a person a man really thinks you are by the earrings he gives you.
I must say, the mind reels.
May I ask whom?
Whom what?
Oh, whom I go to visit you mean.
I guess that's what I mean.
I don't know that I should even discuss it.
Oh, well, they never told me not to tell anyone.
You must cross your heart and kiss your elbow.
I'll try.
You've probably read about him.
His name's Sally Tomato.
Sally Tomato?
Oh, don't look so shocked.
They could never prove for a second that he was even part of the mafia, much less head of it, my dear.
The only thing they did prove was that he cheated at his income tax a little.
Anyway, all I know is that he's a darling old man.
Oh, he was never my lover or anything like that.
In fact, I never knew him until after he was in prison.
But I adore him now.
I mean, I've been going to see him every Thursday for seven months.
Now I think I'd go even if he didn't pay me.
Shoes!
You can only find one.
He pays you?
That's right.
Or anyway, his lawyer does.
If he is a lawyer, which I doubt since he doesn't seem to have an office, only an answering service.
And he always wants to meet you at Hamburger Heaven.
There you are, you sneak.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Dress.
Here we are.
Bag.
There.
Two.
There we are.
Anyway, about seven months ago, this so-called lawyer, Mr. O'Shaughnessy, asked me how I'd like to cheer up a lonely old man and pick up a hundred a week at the same time.
I told him, look, darling, you've got the wrong Holly Golightly.
A girl can do as well as level trips to the powder room.
I mean, any gentleman with the slightest cheek will give a girl a $50 bill for the powder room.
And I always ask for cab fare, too.
That's another 50.
But then he told me his client was Sally Tomato.
He said, dear old Sally had seen me at Elmer's or somewhere.
and had admired me a la distance.
So wouldn't it be a good deed if I went to visit him once a week?
Well, how could I say no?
It was all so wildly romantic.
How do I look?
Very good.
I must say I'm amazed.
You were darling to help.
I could never have done it without you.
Back.
Call me any time.
Just upstairs.
Or I will be as soon as I get moved in.
Bye, Kat.
You mean he gives you $100 for an hour's conversation?
Well, Mr. O'Shaughnessy does as soon as I meet him and give him the weather report.
Look, it's none of my business, but it sounds to me like you could get in a lot of trouble.
Hold this for me, will you?
And what do you mean, weather report?
Oh, there's just a message I give Mr. O'Shaughnessy so he'll know I've really been up there.
Sally tells me things to say like, uh...
Oh, there's a hurricane in Cuba and it's cloudy over Palermo.
Things like that.
You don't have to worry.
I've taken care of myself for a long time.
Taxi!
I never could do that.
It's easy.
I'm late.
I know it.
Don't tell me you were locked out.
Didn't you get the key?
Oh, darling.
I'm so sorry.
No, I got the key all right.
Miss Golightly, my neighbor, was kind enough to let me in.
Miss Golightly's on her way to Sing Sing.
Oh.
Just visiting, of course.
Miss Golightly, Mrs. Phelanson, my decorator.
How do you do?
Ooh, darling.
Let me look at you.
Are you through?
I'm in a terrible rush.
Grand Central Station and step on it, darling.
Is it really only three weeks since I left you in Rome?
Seems like years.
You seen the apartment?
Not yet.
I know it was wicked of me, but I couldn't resist.
I went ahead and fixed it up without you.
I think it's darling, of course, but if you absolutely hate it,
We can rip everything out and start from scratch.
Over the car.
Hey, baby!
Where you going?
Oh, come on, baby.
Open the door.
Oh, be a pal.
You're breaking up a beautiful party.
Come on, baby, open the door.
Hey, the band is swinging.
Oh, come on, baby.
Mr. Golightly, once again, I must protest.
If you don't stop with that phonograph right this minute, I'm going to call the police department.
Well, that's more better.
What's the matter, baby?
Oh, come on.
You're a great kid.
Open the door.
Come on, baby.
I'm waiting for you.
It's all right.
It's only me.
Uh, no, wait a minute, Miss, uh... Golightly.
Holly Golightly.
I live downstairs.
We met this morning, remember?
Yeah.
It's all right.
She's gone.
I must say, she works late hours for a decorator.
The thing is, I have the most terrifying man downstairs.
I mean, he's sweet when he isn't drunk, but let him start lapping up the vino, and, oh, golly, Kel Beast.
Finally got so tiresome down there, just went out the window.
You can throw me out if you want to, but you did look so cozy in here, and your decorative friend had gone home, and it was beginning to get a bit cold out there on the fire escape.
And I always heard people in New York never get to know their neighbors.
Well, how was Sing Sing?
Fine.
I made the tray and everything.
And what's the weather report?
Small craft warnings, Block Island, Hatteras.
Whatever that means.
You know you're sweet?
You really are.
And you look a little like my brother Fred.
Do you mind if I call you Fred?
Not at all.
300.
She's very generous.
Is it by the week, the hour, or what?
OK, the party's over.
Out.
Poor Fred.
Darling Fred, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
Don't be angry.
I was just trying to let you know I understand.
I understand completely.
It's okay.
Stick around.
Make yourself a drink.
Throw me my robe and I'll make you one.
You stay right where you are.
You must be absolutely exhausted.
I mean, it is very late and you were sound asleep and everything.
I suppose you think I'm very brazen or très fou or something.
I don't think you're any fuller than anybody else.
Yes, you do.
Everybody does, and I don't mind.
It's useful being top banana in the shock department.
What do you do, anyway?
I'm a writer, I guess.
You guess, don't you know?
Okay.
Positive statement.
Ringing affirmative.
I'm a writer.
The only writer I would have been out with is Benny Shacklett.
He's written an awful lot of television stuff, but Kel Rath.
Tell me, are you a real writer?
I mean, does anybody buy what you write or publish it or anything?
They bought what's in the box.
Yours?
Mm-hmm.
All these books?
Oh, it's just the one book.
Twelve copies of it.
Nine Lives by Paul Barjack.
They're stories.
Mm-hmm.
Nine of them.
Tell me more.
They're not the kind of stories you can really tell.
Too dirty?
I suppose they're dirty too, but only incidentally.
Mainly they're angry, sensitive, intensely felt, and the dirtiest of all dirty words, promising.
Or so said the Times Book Review, October 1st, 1956.
1956?
That's right.
I suppose this is kind of a ratty question, but what have you written lately?
Lately, I've been working on a novel.
Lately?
Since 1956?
Well, a novel takes a long time.
I want to get it exactly right.
So no more stories?
Well, the idea is I'm supposed to not fritter my talent away on little things.
I'm supposed to be saving it for the big one.
Tell me, do you write every day?
Sure.
Today?
It's a beautiful typewriter.
Of course.
It writes nothing but sensitive, intensely-felt, promising prose.
But there's no ribbon in it.
There isn't?
No.
Oh.
You know, something you said this morning's been bothering me all day.
What's that?
Do they really give you $50 whenever you go to the powder room?
Of course.
You must do very well.
I'm trying to save, but I'm not very good at it.
You know, you do look a lot like my brother Fred.
I haven't seen him, of course, since I was 14.
That's when I left home.
And he was already six foot two.
I guess it must have been the peanut butter that did it.
Everybody thought he was Dottie, the way he gorged himself on peanut butter.
But he wasn't Dottie.
Just sweet and vague and terribly slow.
Poor Fred.
He's in the army now.
That's really the best place for him until I can get enough money saved.
And then?
And then Fred and I...
I went to Mexico once.
It's a wonderful place for raising horses.
I saw one place near the sea that...
Fred's very good with horses.
But even land in Mexico costs something.
And no matter what I do, there never seems to be more than a couple of hundred dollars in the bank.
It can't be 4.30.
It just can't.
Do you mind if I just get in with you for a minute?
It's all right.
Really, it is.
We're friends, that's all.
We are friends, aren't we?
Sure.
OK. Let's don't say another word.
Let's just get one thing straight right now.
I hate snoops.
Lucille, darling?
Two E. Huh?
I've been trying desperately to reach you.
Bill just got back.
A day early, the beast.
So I'm afraid I'll have to beg off.
You'll explain to the rest of the girls?
You're a darling.
Maybe we can have a long lunch tomorrow.
I'll phone you in the morning.
Mm-hmm.
Whatever you say.
And you will manage to survive without me tonight.
Sure.
I might even take a wild, boyish fling at writing.
Good night.
Huh, Polly baby?
Since you're my big mouth.
Buongiorno.
Huh?
Aren't you drinking?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you got pockets there or something?
What do you go by?
What's your name?
What do you call yourself?
Irving.
Oh, yeah, perfect, perfect.
That's wonderful, Irving.
I'll be right back, Irving, baby.
Yeah.
Oh, kid's still in the shower.
You expected?
I was invited.
Is that what you mean?
Oh, now, don't get yourself all tense and sore, pal.
Come on in.
It's a party.
There's a lot of characters coming around here.
They're not expected.
I'll buy you a drink.
You drink?
Yeah.
I'll buy you a drink.
OK. Yeah.
Hey, honey, you're a stead split, man.
What do you drink, kid?
Bourbon.
All right.
On the rocks?
Yeah.
Good.
No, with water.
All right.
You mind rocks first, then, won't you?
Uh, yeah.
Good.
You got it.
Not too much.
All right.
Yeah, that'll set you free.
You not a kid long?
Not very.
I live upstairs.
You're kidding.
Oh, look at this place, will you?
What a place.
It's unbelievable.
What a thump.
Hmm?
Huh.
What do you think?
About what?
Is she or isn't she?
Wait a minute.
Hold it down.
Harriet!
J-P-O-J.
What is that?
All right.
You know Gil.
Yeah, how are you, Gil?
Good to see you.
How about a drink?
Fine.
In the kitchen, you'll find everything you need.
Thanks.
Yeah.
So... Oh, honey, that is you.
That is you.
Fred, darling, I'm so glad you could come.
I brought you a house present.
Something to book this.
Oh, you're sweet.
There.
Doesn't that look nice?
Give me a cigarette, O.J.
Sure, sure.
O.J.'
's a great agent.
He knows a terrific lot of phone numbers.
What's Jerry Wall's phone number, O.J.?
Oh, come on.
Lay off.
Darling, I want you to call him and tell him what a genius Fred is.
Yes, I got it.
Stop blushing, Fred.
You didn't say you were a genius.
I did.
So quit stalling, O.J.
Just tell me what you're going to do to make Fred rich and famous.
Now, why don't you let Fred baby me settle that matter, huh, puppy?
Okay, but just remember, I'm the agent.
He's already got a decorator.
I'm the agent.
Hold it, hold it.
All right, boys, come on in here.
Right in the kitchen, you'll find everything you need.
So, listen, Fred baby.
What do you think?
No, it's Paul baby.
Oh, it is?
I thought it was Fred baby.
No.
Well, answer the question now.
Is she or isn't she?
Is she or isn't she what?
A phony.
I don't know.
I don't think so.
You don't think so, huh?
Well, you're wrong.
She is.
But on the other hand, you're right.
Because she's a real phony.
You know why?
because she honestly believes all this phony junk that she believes.
I mean it.
Now, look, I like the kid.
I mean, I sincerely like the kid.
I do.
I mean, I'm sensitive, that's why.
I mean, you gotta be sensitive to like the kid, you know what I mean?
It's what you call a touch, a streak of the poet, you know what I mean?
You known her long?
Are you kidding?
I'm the guy that discovered her.
I'm O.J.
Berman.
A couple of years ago, back in the coast, she was just a kid.
Of course, she had a lot of style, a lot of class, you know.
A lot of what?
Class, yeah.
She had a lot of class.
But, of course, when she opened her mouth, you didn't know what she was talking about.
She was a hillbilly ranoke.
You know how long it took me to smooth out that accent?
No, I'll tell you how long.
One year.
You know how we did it?
We gave her French lessons.
Yeah, figured once she could imitate French, she had no trouble imitating English.
And finally, when I thought she was be ready, I arranged for a little screen test.
Well, the night before the screen test, well, I could have killed myself.
The night before the screen test, the phone rings.
I pick it up.
I said, OJ speaking.
She says, this is Holly.
I said, Holly, Holly, you sound so far away, honey.
What's with you?
She says, I'm in New York.
I said, what kind of New York?
You got a screen test tomorrow.
She says, I'm in New York because I've never been to New York before.
I said, get yourself on the plane.
Get back here.
She says, I don't want it.
I said, what do you mean you don't want it?
What do you want?
She says, I don't want it.
I says, what do you want?
She says, when I find out what I want, I'm going to let you know.
Bang.
So look, Fred, baby, you know, don't tell me.
This is Paul, baby.
Paul, baby, sure.
I mean, don't tell me that she isn't a phony.
You know what I mean?
Irving.
Honey Irving, where have you been?
She's been running around.
You look so wonderful.
I know, and after all that she said about him, and he knows that I'm gonna be there, and he brings it, and she just talks like a baby.
Molly!
I know, especially when he does it.
Time, darling.
What?
The time.
Do you have a watch?
No, I don't.
Oh, let me see a minute.
It's 6.45.
Thank you so much, dear.
Can I borrow it?
I don't know how to call it.
This is some party.
Who are all these people, anyhow?
Who knows?
The word gets out.
You don't mind, do you, darling?
Reinforcements.
Holly!
Holly, my darling!
What's that?
Mag Wildwood.
She's a model, believe it or not, and a thumping bore.
But just look at the goodies she brought with her.
She's all right, I suppose, if you like dark, handsome, rich-looking men with passionate natures and too many teeth.
I don't mean that one.
I mean the other one.
The other one?
It's Rusty Trawler.
Hmm?
Rusty Trawler.
He happens to be the ninth richest man in America under 50.
Now, that indeed is a remarkable piece of information to have at your fingertips.
I keep track of these things.
Excuse me, you owe me 40...
Hold this for me, will you, darling?
Oh, it was so romantic.
Mag, darling, what are you doing here?
Honey, I was upstairs working with Unioshi Easter stuff for the bazaar.
Then these two nice boys came to pick me up.
It was a mistaken course.
My wires got crossed somewhere.
They were both very sweet about it.
May I present Jose Silva Pereira.
He's from Brazil.
Mr. Golatly.
Very kind of you, Miss Godlightly, to allow me to attend your party.
I'm so interested in North American culture.
I've been already, of course, to the Statue of Liberty and to the Restaurant Automatique, but this is the first time I'm in a typical North American home.
Wouldn't he just melt in your mouth?
And this is Mr. Rusty Trawler, Mr. Colato.
You're now vexed of me for bringing him.
Of course not, darling.
I'm glad.
Now, who's going to bring me a bourbon?
O.J.?
Yeah.
Would you get Miss Wildwood a drink?
Yeah, which one's Miss Wildwood?
Mr.
Bourbon.
We have been formally introduced by our mad Wildwood from Wildwood, Arkansas.
That's...
Hill Country.
Now you just make yourself right at home, senor.
Oh, do not trouble yourself.
I'm content to stand observing the customs of your country.
Okay, you do that.
Now come along, Mr. Trawler.
Let's see what we can find to amuse you with.
and at the last minute, I had Gil call... Look, I wasn't supposed to pick you up here or any...
Yes.
Miss Gold, I think this time I'm warning you, I am definitely this time going to call in the police.
Something important?
No, just the guy upstairs.
Complaining about the noise.
He's angry.
Well, he did mention something about calling the police.
Oh, the police.
The police.
Oh, that I cannot have.
I'd better look for Miss Wildwood and go.
Do you think I'd find a bull of mine moused after a piece of cheap Hollywood crap?
Mac, darling, you're being a bull.
Shut up!
You...
You know what's gonna happen to you?
I am gonna march you over to the zoo and feed you to the yak.
As soon as I finish this trick.
Good evening, Ed.
It's Paul, baby.
Oh, yes.
You remember Irving, don't you?
Yeah, hi, Irving.
Ed, this is Jose.
Nice to meet you, Jose.
Wonderful seeing you.
Yes.
Jewel thieves.
I have no head for figures at all.
I'm trying desperately to save some money.
You know, I told you.
I just can't seem to.
He makes me write down everything in there.
What I get, what I spend.
I used to have a checking account, but he made me get rid of that.
He feels, for me anyway, that it's better to operate on a cash basis, tax-wise.
Someday, Mr.
Friend, you take this book, turn it into a novel,
Everything is there.
Just fill in a little of the details.
Certainly would be good for some laughs.
No.
No, I don't think so.
This is a book would break the heart.
Mr. Fitzsimmons, powder room, $50.
Less, $18.
Repair, one black satin dress.
Cat food, 27 cents.
Sally, darling, please stop making me blush.
But you're right about Jack Fitzsimmons.
He's an absolute rat.
I guess, of course, I don't really know anybody but rats.
Except, of course, Fred here.
You do think Fred is nice, don't you, Sally?
For you, I hope he is.
Give me a kiss goodbye, baby.
Goodbye, Uncle Sally.
Till next week.
Goodbye, and don't forget to send that book, eh?
I won't.
Oh, what about the weather report?
Oh, yes.
Snow flurries expected this weekend in New Orleans.
Snow flurries expected this weekend in New Orleans?
Isn't that just the weirdest?
I bet they haven't had snow in New Orleans for a million years.
I don't know how he thinks them up.
What are you doing?
Writing.
Good.
Well, hello.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
It's probably nothing.
I want to see if he's still there.
See if who's still there?
What are you talking about?
See?
I noticed him yesterday afternoon.
I didn't say anything.
I didn't want to sound neurotic, but when he's there again today... Who do you think he is?
Well, it could be anybody, of course, but what crossed my mind was...
Suppose Bill's having us watched, huh?
Okay, I'll take care of this.
No, no, don't, please.
Look, if that's what it is, you'll only make everything worse.
I'll be careful.
You wait here.
Darling, please don't.
I don't think you should.
Now, take it easy.
I just want to find out what this is all about.
What do you want?
Son, I need a friend.
That's me.
That's her.
That's her brother Fred.
You're Holly's father?
Her name ain't Holly.
She was Lula Mae Barnes.
Was till she married me.
I'm her husband, Doc O'Lightly.
Paul Varjack.
I'm a horse doctor, animal man.
Do some farming, too, near Tulip, Texas.
Her brother Fred's getting out of the army soon.
Lula Mae belongs home with her husband, her brother, and her children.
Them's her children?
She's got four children.
Now, son, I didn't claim they was her natural born children.
Their own precious mother, precious woman, passed away July the 4th, Independence Day, 1955, the year of the drought.
When I married Lula Mae, she was going on 14.
Now, you might think the average person going on 14 wouldn't know the old mine, but you take Lula Mae,
She was an exceptional person.
I'll tell you, son, she just plumb broke our hearts when she ran off like she done.
Just plain had no reason.
All the housework was done by her daughters.
Lula May could just take it easy.
I tell you, that woman got positively fat.
What, her brother?
He growed up into a giant.
Which is a sight different from the way they come to us.
Couple of wild young'uns they was.
I caught them outside the house stealing milk and turkey eggs.
Zulu Mae and her brother had been living with some mean no-com people about a hundred miles east of Tulum.
She had good cause to run off from that house.
Never had none to leave mine.
What about her brother?
Didn't he leave too?
No, sir.
We had Fred with us till he took him in the army.
That's what I come to talk to her about.
I had a letter from him.
He's getting out of the army in February.
That's why I got on a Greyhound bus to come to get her.
Lula Mae's place is with her husband, her children, and her brother.
Huh?
Surprised me, Crackerjack.
You want it?
Uh-uh.
Never could understand why that woman run off.
Don't tell me she wasn't happy.
Talky as a jaybird, she was.
Something smart to say on every subject.
Better than the radio.
And I proposed, I cried like a baby.
She said, what do you want to cry for, Doc?
Of course we'll be married.
I've never been married before.
Well, I had to laugh and hug and squeeze her.
Never been married before.
Listen, son, I advise you I need a friend.
Because I don't want to surprise her or scare her or nothing.
Be my friend.
Let her know I'm here.
Will you do that for me, son?
Yeah, sure, doc.
If that's what you want.
Come on.
I was supposed to be at 21 half an hour ago.
Maybe we can have a drink or something tomorrow, huh?
Sure, Lula Mae.
If you're still here tomorrow.
Oh, please.
Where is he?
Fred?
Gosh.
Lula Mae.
Don't they feed you up here?
You're so skinny.
Hi, Doc.
Gosh, little me.
Kingdom come.
What's the matter?
Are you all right?
I guess so.
No, I'm not.
Fred, will you help me?
If I can.
I want you to come to the bus station with us.
Darken me.
What?
He still thinks I'm going back with him.
I need support.
I don't think I can play the scene alone.
Holly, what can I do?
He's your husband.
No, he's not.
He's not?
It was annulled ages ago, but he just won't accept it.
Please, Fred.
I'll tell him you're coming to see us off.
Don't say anything.
Just meet us out front in about an hour.
Please?
You wait right here, honey.
I'll get the bag.
Why don't I get some magazines?
Please, Fred.
Don't leave me.
Attention, please.
Leaving from Platform 5.
Philadelphia, Columbus, Indianapolis...
Come on, Lula Mae, that's us.
Doc, I'm not coming with you.
Come on.
Let's walk together quietly and I'll try and help you understand.
Help me talk to him, Fred.
That's all right, son.
I appreciate you want to help, but it's between Lula Mae and me.
Sure, Doc.
I love you, Lula Mae.
I know you do, and that's just the trouble.
It's a mistake you always made, Doc, trying to love a wild thing.
You were always lugging home wild things.
Once it was a hawk with a broken wing, and another time it was a full-grown wildcat with a broken leg.
Remember?
Little me, there's something... You mustn't give your heart to a wild thing.
The more you do, the stronger they get.
Until they're strong enough to run into the woods or fly into a tree.
And then to a higher tree, and then to the sky.
Little me, there's something I gotta tell you.
Excuse me?
A couple of weeks ago, I got a letter from young Fred.
Fred?
He's all right, isn't he?
Yeah, he's fine.
I guess he's getting out of the army in February.
That's what he wrote to tell me.
February?
Well, it's only four months.
So, you see, you've got to come back with me, Lulu Mae.
Your place is with me and your chariot and your brother.
Doc, you've got to understand I can't come back.
And you've got to understand what I'm trying to tell you.
I don't want to seem like I'm pressuring you none, but now I've got to.
If you don't come back with me, I'm going to have to write young Fred and tell him that unless he wants to look out for himself, he'd better sign up for another hitch.
Doc, don't you do that.
Don't you write that to him.
I'll write to him myself and tell him I want him here with me.
I'll take care of him, don't you worry.
You're talking crazy, Lula Mae.
Doc, stop calling me that.
I'm not Lula Mae anymore.
All right, Lula Mae.
I guess you know what you're doing.
Keep an eye on her, will you, son?
At least see she eats something once in a while.
Sure, Doc.
So skinny.
Please understand.
I love you, but I'm just not Lula Mae anymore.
I'm not.
You know the terrible thing, Fred darling?
I am still Lula Mae.
14 years old, stealing turkey eggs and running through a briar patch.
Except now I call it having the mean reds.
Well, it's still too early to go to Tiffany's.
I guess the next best thing is a drink.
Yes, I very much need a drink.
Will you buy me one, Fred, darling?
Sure.
Only promise me one thing.
Don't take me home until I'm drunk.
Until I'm very drunk indeed.
Do you think she's talented, deeply and importantly talented?
No.
Amusingly and superficially talented, yes, but deeply and importantly, no.
Hmm?
Oh, indeed.
Well, let me tell you something, mister.
If I had her money, I'd be richer than she is.
How do you figure that?
Because I'd keep the candy store.
Old Sally Tomato, that's my candy store.
I'd always keep Sally.
And that's why I'd be richer than she is.
We'd better get a little more air.
Tom, Dick, and Harry.
No correction.
Every Tom, Dick, and Sid.
Harry was his friend.
Anyway, every Tom, Dick, and Sid thinks that if he takes a girl to dinner, she'll just crawl up like a kitten in a little furry ball at his feet.
Right?
I have, by actual count, been taken to dinner by 26 different rats in the last two months.
27 if you count Benny Shackley, who's in many ways a super rat.
I think I forgot my key.
Never mind.
I just buzzed Juniyoshi.
Oh.
Do you want to know something funny?
Mm-hmm?
In spite of the fact that most of these rats fork up $50 for the powder room like little dolls...
I find I have again, by actual count, $9 less in the old bank account than I had six months ago.
So, my darling Fred, I have tonight made a very serious decision.
And what is that?
No longer will I play the field.
Congratulations.
The field stinks, both economically and socially.
And I am giving it up.
What?
Miss Gulayli!
and the New York State Housing Commission, and if necessary, the Board of Health.
Quiet up there.
You want to wake the whole house?
As Miss Goliath was saying before she was so rudely interrupted, Miss Goliath further announces her intentions to devote her not inconsiderable talents to the immediate capture, for the purpose of matter, honey, of Mr. Rutherford.
Rusty to his friends in his room.
I'm sure he has many.
Trawler.
Who?
Rusty Trawler.
You met him at my party a couple of weeks ago.
He came with Mag Wildwood.
Not the beautiful Latin title.
The other one.
The one that looks like a pig.
Remember?
The ninth richest man in America under 50?
Ah, do I detect a look of disapproval in your eye?
Tough beans, buddy, because that's the way it's going to be.
Hi, Kat.
Holly, you're drunk.
True.
Absolutely true.
Truly Buddy Rumble.
What are you doing?
So I think we should have a drink to the new Mrs. Rusty Trawler.
Meet
Hey, take it easy.
What's the matter?
Don't you think I can do it?
Tell me.
Seriously, I'm interested.
Don't you think I can?
You heard the doc.
My brother gets out of the army in February and the doc won't take him back.
So it's all up to me.
I don't know why you don't understand.
I need money.
I'll do whatever I have to do to get it.
So?
This time next month, I'll be the new Mrs. Rusty Trawler.
And I think we should have a little drink to that.
It's all gone.
Isn't that too bad?
Got any whiskey upstairs?
But you've had enough.
Go ahead, get the whiskey.
I'll pay you for it.
Holly, please.
No, no, you disapprove of me.
And I do not accept drinks from gentlemen who disapprove of me.
I'll pay for my own whiskey, and don't you forget it.
Holly.
I do not accept drinks from disapproving gentlemen.
Especially not disapproving gentlemen who are kept by other ladies.
So take it.
You should be used to taking money from ladies by now.
If I were you, I'd be more careful with my money.
Rusty trawler is too hard a way of earning it.
It should take you exactly four seconds to cross from here to that door.
I'll give you two.
I came up to talk to you about it the other night.
Then I saw the paper and... Well, actually, I'm kind of embarrassed about it.
But since it concerns you, I thought I'd talk to you about it in person.
What?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, the earplugs.
I can't go through the whole thing again.
Sufficient to say, I've come to make up.
And as an added inducement, I have all kinds of news.
Can I come in?
I guess so.
Just a minute.
Do I have a nightgown on?
No, I don't.
Would you mind turning around for a second?
Oh, never mind.
It's such a corny line anyway.
I'll turn it around myself.
Come in.
Have you seen the paper?
Mm.
Rusty, you mean?
Mm-hmm.
Yes, I know all about it.
Suddenly had him pegged wrong, didn't I?
I thought he was just a rat.
He was a super rat all along.
A super rat in rat clothing.
You don't even know the best part.
Not only was he a rat, but a super rat, rather.
He was also broke.
Broke?
I mean, but not a farthing.
His family has money, of course, but he personally is broke.
Turns out he owes $700,000.
Can you imagine anyone owing $700,000?
Forty-three dollars, yes.
Anyway, that's why he decided to marry the queen of the pig people.
I'll tell you one thing, Fred, darling.
I'd marry you for your money in a minute.
Would you marry me for my money?
In a minute.
So I guess it's pretty lucky neither of us is rich, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, Fred, darling, I'm so glad to see you.
What have you been doing?
Writing, mostly.
Sold a story.
Just got word this morning.
Oh, that's marvelous.
It really is.
But only how does your decorator friend feel about it?
I thought you were supposed to be saving yourself and all of that.
You know something?
I haven't quite got around to telling her about it yet.
Look, why don't we go out and have a drink or take a walk or something to celebrate?
All right.
I think there's some champagne in the icebox.
Why don't you open it while I get dressed?
Okay.
I don't think I've ever drunk champagne before breakfast before.
With breakfast on several occasions, but never before before.
Now, I've got a wonderful idea.
We could spend the whole day doing things we've never done before.
We'll take turns for something you've never done and me.
Of course, I can't really think of anything I've never done.
I've never been for a walk in the morning before.
At least not since I've been in New York.
I've walked up Fifth Avenue at 6, but as far as I'm concerned, that's till night.
Do you think it counts?
Sure it counts.
Now we're even.
Don't you just love it?
Love what?
Tiffany's.
Isn't it wonderful?
Do you see what I mean, how nothing bad could ever happen to you in a place like this?
It isn't that I give a hoot about jewelry, except diamonds, of course.
Like that.
What do you think?
Well... Of course, personally, I think it'd be tacky to wear diamonds before I'm 40.
Well, you're right.
But in the meantime, you should have something.
I'll wait.
No, I'm going to buy you a present.
You bought me one, a typewriter ribbon, and it brought me luck.
All right, but Tiffany's can be pretty expensive.
I've got my check and $10.
Oh, I wouldn't let you cash a check, but a present for $10 or under, that I'll accept.
Of course, I don't exactly know what we're going to find at Tiffany's for $10.
May I help you?
Perhaps.
Actually, we were looking for a present for the lady.
Certainly, sir.
Is there something special you had in mind?
Well, we had considered diamonds.
Now, I don't want to offend you, but the lady feels that diamonds are tacky for her.
Oh, I think they're divine on older women, but I don't think they'd be right for me.
You do understand.
Certainly.
In all fairness, I think I ought to explain there is also a secondary problem.
one of finance.
We can only afford to spend a limited amount.
May I ask how limited?
Ten dollars.
That was the outside figure, yes.
I see.
Do you have anything for ten dollars?
Well, frankly, madam, within that price range, the variety of merchandise is rather limited.
However, I do think we might have, let me see, strictly as a novelty, you understand?
for the lady and gentleman who has everything, a sterling silver telephone dialer at 675, including tax.
Sterling silver telephone dialer?
Yes, at 675, including federal tax.
Well, the price is right, but I must say I'd rather hope for something slightly more, how shall I say it, romantic in feeling.
What do you think?
As sterling silver telephone dialers go, I certainly think it's handsome, but you do understand.
Well, we tried, but I guess we could have something engraved, couldn't we?
Yes, I suppose so.
Yes, indeed.
The only problem is you would more or less have to buy something first, if only in order to have some object upon which to place the engraving.
You see the difficulty?
Well, we could have this engraved, couldn't we?
I think would be very smart.
This, I take it, was not purchased at Tiffany's?
No.
Actually, it was purchased concurrent with, uh... well, actually came inside of... well, a box of Cracker Jack.
I see.
Do they still really have prizes in Cracker Jack boxes?
Oh, yes.
That's nice to know.
It gives one a feeling of solidarity.
almost of continuity with the past that sort of thing.
do you think Tiffany's would really engrave it for us?
I mean you don't think they would feel it was beneath them or anything like that?
well it is rather unusual madam.
but I think you'll find that Tiffany's is very understanding.
if you will tell me what initials you would like I think we could have something ready for you in the morning.
didn't I tell you this was a lovely place?
What is this place, anyway?
You said you wanted to sit down.
It's the public library.
You never been here?
No.
That makes two for me.
I don't see any books.
They're in there.
Each one of these little drawers is stuffed with little cards.
And each little card is a book or an author.
D-A-R-J-A-K. Really?
Look.
Isn't it marvelous?
There you are, right in the public library.
Bar Jack Paul, nine lives.
I mean, a lot of numbers.
Do you think they really have the book itself?
Live?
Do you follow me?
57.
That's us.
57, please.
Nine Lives by Varjak Paul.
Did you ever read it?
It's absolutely marvelous.
No, I'm afraid I haven't.
Well, you should.
He wrote it.
He's Varjak Paul in person.
She doesn't believe me.
Show her your driver's license or Dinah's Club card or something.
Honest, he really is the author.
Cross my heart and kiss my elbow.
Would you kindly lower your voice, miss?
Why don't you autograph to them?
You think it'd be nice?
Sort of make it more personal?
Really, miss.
Go ahead.
Don't be so stuck up.
Autograph it to them.
All right.
What shall I say?
Something sentimental, I think.
What are you doing?
Stop that!
Shh!
You're defacing public property.
Well, all right, if that's the way you feel.
Come on, Fred Dung, let's get out of here.
I don't think this place is half as nice as Tiffany's.
Hey, did you ever steal anything from a 5 and 10?
When you were a kid, I mean.
No.
I'm the sensitive, bookish type.
Did you?
I used to.
I still do every now and then, sort of to keep my hand in.
Come on, don't be chicken.
Anyway, you've never done it, and it's your turn.
the house at home?
Ollie?
You know that, don't you?
But I love you anyway.
Tooie.
Yeah?
I've got to talk to you.
All right.
You want a drink?
Uh-uh.
This is going to be a serious discussion, and suddenly I'm terribly afraid it is.
You're going to have to take off that ridiculous mask.
Or else I'm going to have to wear one, too.
Tuli, look, please.
What's the matter?
Girl trouble?
Is that it, darling?
Oh, I see.
Well, that's not so serious.
As a matter of fact, I've been expecting it.
I can't say I like it, but I've been expecting it.
Who is she?
Hasn't got anything to do with her.
This is between you and me.
Oh, then it is serious.
Well, now.
Louie, you're a very stylish girl.
Can't we end this stylishly?
End it?
Yes.
I do believe love has found Andy Hardy.
Let's see.
A waitress?
A sales girl?
No.
She'd have to be someone rich, wouldn't she, Paul?
Someone who could help you.
Curiously enough, she's a girl who can't help anyone, not even herself.
The thing is, I can help her.
And it's a nice feeling for a change.
All right.
I understand.
I'll tell you what, Paul.
I am a very stylish girl.
What are you doing?
Writing a check.
Don't look so bewildered.
Surely you've noticed me writing checks before.
Pay to the order of poor Varjack $1,000.
Take her away somewhere for a week.
You're entitled to a vacation with pay.
Simply a matter of fair labor practice, darling.
Of course, if you were really smart, you'd get some of the other boys together and organize a union.
That way you'd get all the fringe benefits.
Hospitalization, a pension plan, and unemployment insurance when you're... How shall I put it?
Thanks for making it easier for me.
Don't be ridiculous, darling.
Take the check and call your girl.
No, thanks.
I got a check of my own.
When you get yourself a new rider to help, try and find one my size.
That way, you won't have to even shorten the sleeves.
Thank you.
Looks like a girl I know named Holly.
Really?
I'm sorry.
I'm busy.
What are you doing?
Reading.
South America, land of wealth and promise.
It's very interesting.
Let's get out of here.
I said, let's get out of here.
I want to talk to you.
Shh.
What's the matter with you anyway?
What's happened?
Fred, would you please just leave me alone?
Holly, I love you.
Where are you going?
To the ladies' room.
What's the matter with you anyway?
Let me go.
No.
Fred, please let me go.
Let's get something straight.
I am not now, nor have I ever been Fred.
Nor am I Benny Shacklett, whoever he may be.
My name is Paul.
Paul Varjack, and I love you.
Let me go.
Not till we get this settled.
Now, what's all this jazz about South America?
I thought if I'm going to marry a South American, I'd better find out something about the country.
Marry?
What South American?
Jose.
Who the hell's Jose?
Jose de Silva Pereira.
Who the hell's Jose de Silva Pereira?
Darling, you met him.
I know you did.
Mag Wildwood's friend.
The tall, good-looking one who came to the party with Rusty.
Well, my dear, you won't believe this.
But it turns out not only is he handsome and wildly rich, he's absolutely cuckoo for me.
You're crazy.
What, do you think you own me?
That's exactly what I think.
I know, I know.
That's what everybody always thinks.
But everybody happens to be wrong.
Well, I am not everybody.
Or am I?
Is that what you really think?
That I'm no different from all your other rats and super rats?
Wait a minute.
If that's it, if that's what you really think, there's something I want to give you.
What's that?
$50 for the powder room.
in such a mess I couldn't bear to face it alone.
No, you have a message.
No.
Olly.
Good evening, Mr. Yunioshi.
Good evening.
Please, you must leave.
What did you do to her?
Nothing.
There was a telegram and then this.
Crushing everything, conducting like a crazy.
It's appalling.
I can't have a public scandal.
It's too delicate.
I name my position, my family.
Will there be the police again, you think?
I don't see why.
There's no law against busting up your own apartment.
Where is the telegram?
There it is.
Received notice young Fred killed.
In a jeep accident, Fort Riley, Kansas.
Your husband and children joined in the sorrow of our mutual loss.
Letter following, Love Doc.
Brother Fred.
Oh.
His brother, was she very close to him?
Yeah.
What can one do?
Try to help her.
I tried.
It didn't do much good.
You got a ranch or something down in Brazil, don't you?
Yes.
That's good.
She'll like that.
Well, you better get in there.
The three children are still children.
Mrs. Magalhães is Mrs. Magalhães' wife.
Mr. Magalhães is Mrs. Magalhães' husband.
Hi.
Hello.
I got your wire.
How'd you know where to reach me?
Oh, I tried everything.
Called people, asked around, and suddenly thought of looking in the phone book.
Anyway, I'm glad you could come.
You look fine.
You think so?
Oh, I'm fat as a pig, and I haven't had my hair done in months.
But I'm happy, really happy.
Probably shows.
You look très distingué yourself.
I've got a job.
I've been writing a little.
I know.
I've read three of your stories.
Two in the New Yorker and one in that funny little magazine.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
I've taken up knitting.
So I see.
Probably look, uh, very nice once it's finished.
Actually, I'm a little nervous about it.
Jose brought up the blueprints for a new ranch house he's building.
I have this strange feeling that maybe the blueprints and my knitting instructions got switched.
I mean, it isn't impossible that I'm knitting a ranch house.
Really, darling, I can't tell you how divinely happy I am.
What is that, anyhow?
Portuguese.
A very complicated language.
4,000 irregular verbs.
I think you're liking...
Very impressive.
What's it mean?
I believe you are in league with the butcher.
Holly, what's this about?
Why did you want to see me?
Jose's in Washington for the night, so I thought if I asked you over, you might come.
Well, I've said goodbye to everyone else I care about.
You're going somewhere?
I'm going to Rio tomorrow.
I've got the plane ticket, and I've even said goodbye to old Sally.
Jose's flying down with you.
Well, we're going on separate planes, of course.
He doesn't think it would look right for us to be traveling together.
His family's very important down there, so he has to worry about things like that.
Anyway, I thought I'd show off and cook dinner for us.
It'll be fun eating in.
Did I tell you how divinely and utterly happy I am?
Yes.
You are getting married, then?
Well, he hasn't really asked me, not in so many words.
Four, you mean?
Huh?
Well, that's how many words it takes.
Will you marry me?
Oh, we'll get married, all right.
I know we will.
And in church and with his family there and everything.
And that's why he's waiting till we get to Rio.
Probably.
Do you think it's trying to tell us something?
I hope you like chicken and saffron rice served with chocolate sauce.
It's an East Indian classic, my dear.
Three months ago, I couldn't scramble eggs.
Oh, golly, darling, I did so want to impress you.
Look, I'm not much for chicken with sauce anyway.
Why don't we go out somewhere?
Let me buy you a farewell dinner.
Oh, that would be fun.
As long as it's someplace I can go like this.
Years from now, years and years, I'll be back.
Me and my nine Brazilian brats.
They'll be dark like Jose, of course, but they'll have bright, green, beautiful eyes.
I'll bring them back, all right, because they must see this.
Oh, I love New York.
Then why are you leaving?
What's in it for you anyway?
Look, I know what you're thinking, and I don't blame you.
I've always thrown out such a jazzy line.
But really, except for darken yourself, Jose's my first non-rat romance.
Not that he's my idea of the absolute finito.
He's too prim and cautious to be my absolute ideal.
Now, if I could choose from anybody alive, I wouldn't pick Jose.
Nero, maybe, or Albert Schweitzer.
Or Lennon Bernstein.
But I am mad about Jose.
I honestly think I'd give up smoking if he asked me.
Come on, darling, let's eat.
It's getting late.
I'm leaving tomorrow and I haven't even begun to pack.
The one who's here to think I'm the kind of girl who loses her pee.
So I have 26 of them made.
No, wait, I've got a better idea.
Kind of a farewell gesture.
Somebody must have tripped the lock.
Ah, crafty devil, that Yuniyoshi.
Wake up, wake up!
The British are coming!
Or, in this case, the Brazilians.
Exactly.
Oh, I forgot to clean up all that rice.
Hey, you know... Hey!
Ah!
There she are, Lieutenant!
The Walter woman!
There!
Kronberger.
Narcotic squad.
What do you mean?
What's going on?
Sorry, tomato!
They smoke more than tomatoes!
Look around for narcotic!
They've got brandy narcotic in that!
Come on!
What's your name?
Varjak.
Hold it down over there!
Paul Varjak.
V-A-R-J-A-K. Hey!
Now get lost, will ya?
Get out!
I'm a writer.
W-R-I-T-E-R. One at a time.
One at a time.
Now, darling, why don't you start?
Is it true you carried messages from Tomato and Code?
Of course not.
I just meet Mr. O'Shaughnessy at Hamburger Heaven and give him the weather report.
Simply do not ask me what this is all about.
Pas ce que je ne sais pas, monsieur.
But you did used to visit Tomato.
I used to see him every week.
What's wrong with that?
Now, you must have known Tomato was part of the narcotics syndicate.
Mr. Tomato never mentioned narcotics to me.
Makes me furious the way all these wretched people keep persecuting him.
He's a deeply sensitive person.
A darling old man.
Then you're innocent.
Of course I'm innocent.
What are you going to do about it?
What do you mean?
Well, who's your lawyer?
I don't know.
Mr. O'Shaughnessy, I guess.
Mr. O'Shaughnessy.
Grinch, get out of here.
All right, come on.
Let's get a move.
Come on.
Mr. O'Shaughnessy?
Oh, shut up.
Get in there.
Yeah.
Mr. Paul Varjack?
Ready with Mr. Berman in Hollywood.
Kindly deposit $3 for the first three minutes, please.
Hello?
Old Jay Berman here.
Who's calling?
Mr. Berman, this is Paul Varjack.
Nice to talk to you, kid.
Varjack.
V-A-R-J-A-K.
I'm a friend of Holly's.
I met you at a party in New York.
Who?
Paul.
Paul Farjack.
V-A-R... Mr. Berman, this is Fred.
Oh, Fred baby, huh?
You call me about the kid, huh?
Everything's under control, just relax.
I spoke to my lawyer in New York.
I told them to take care of everything, send me the bill, but to keep my name anonymous.
What?
Unknown.
I don't want any part of it.
You hear me?
You sound like you're in a tunnel.
Oh, that's this executive phone I have.
What?
Executive phone.
Hey, baby, they only got her in 10,000 bail.
My lord can get her out till 10 o'clock this morning.
I'll tell you what you do.
You bust into that dump she lives in, collect all the junk,
Get out of the jail, get her out, and take her straight over to a hotel under her phony name, right?
You want to keep away from the reporters as much as possible.
You know what I mean?
Will you do that?
Sure, Mr. Berman.
I can't tell you how much I appreciate you.
Forget it.
I owe her something.
Not that I owe her anything.
I mean, if you really want to get right down to it.
She's a crazy.
She's a phony.
But she's a real phony.
Know what I mean, kid?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Thanks, Mr. Berman.
Thanks a lot.
Right.
Why don't you behave?
Hotel night.
I did a little housebreaking while you were away.
Clayton Hotel driver, 84th and Madison.
O.J.
thinks it'd be a good idea if you stayed out of sight for a while.
I got most of your stuff here, including Kat.
He's all right.
Yeah.
Hello, cat.
Poor no-name slob.
Listen, darling, did you find that plane ticket?
Right here.
We can cash it in.
Cash it in?
Are you kidding?
What time is it?
A little after 10.
Good.
Idle Wild Airport, please, driver.
Never mind.
You can't do that.
Why not?
You don't understand.
You're under indictment.
If they catch you jumping, they'll lock you up and throw away the key.
Don't be ridiculous, darling.
By the day after tomorrow, I'll be married to the future president of Brazil.
And that'll give me diplomatic immunity or something.
I wouldn't bet on it.
What is it, darling?
A message for you.
Oh.
Oh, yes, I see.
Did he bring it in person, or was it just there, shoved under the door?
A cousin.
Hand me my purse, will you, darling?
A girl can't read that sort of thing without her lipstick.
You read to me, will you, darling?
I don't think I'm quite there.
Sure you want me to?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
My dearest little girl, I have loved you knowing you were not as others...
but conceive of my despair upon discovering in such a brutal and public style how very different you are from the manner of woman a man of my position could hope to make his wife.
I grieve for the disgrace of your present circumstances, and I do not find it in my heart to add my condemn to the condemn that surrounds you.
So I hope you will find it in your heart not to condemn me,
I have my family to protect in my name, and I am a coward where these institutions enter.
Forget me, beautiful child, and may God be with you.
Jose.
Well?
Well, at least he's honest.
It's kind of touching.
Touching?
That's square ball jazz.
He says he's a coward.
All right, so he's not a regular rat or even a super rat.
He's just a scared little mouse, that's all.
But oh, golly!
Gee darn!
Wow.
So much for South America.
I didn't really think you were cut out to be queen of the pampas anyway.
Clayton Hotel.
Idlewild.
The plane leaves at 12, and on it I plan to be.
Holly, you can't.
Et pourquoi pas?
I'm not hot-footing it after Jose, if that's what you think.
Oh, no.
As far as I'm concerned, he's the future president of nowhere.
It's only why should I waste a perfectly good plane ticket?
Besides, I've never been to Brazil.
Please, darling, don't sit there looking at me like that.
I'm going, and that's all there is to it.
Now, all they want from me or my services is a state's witness against Sally.
Nobody has any intention of prosecuting me.
To begin with, they don't have a ghost of a chance.
Even so, this town's finished for me, at least for a while.
There are certain shades of limelight that can wreck a girl's complexion.
They'll have the rope up at every saloon in town.
I'll tell you what you do for me, darling.
When you get back to town, I want you to call up the New York Times or whoever you call.
I want you to mail me a list of the 50 richest men in Brazil.
The 50 richest!
Holly, I'm not going to let you do this.
You're not going to let me.
Holly, I'm in love with you.
So what?
So plenty.
I love you.
You belong to me.
No.
People don't belong to people.
Of course they do.
I'm not going to let anyone put me in a cage.
I don't want to put you in a cage.
I want to love you.
It's the same thing.
No, it's not.
Holly?
I'm not Holly.
I'm not Lula Mae either.
I don't know who I am.
I'm like Cat here.
We're a couple of no-name slobs.
We belong to nobody, and nobody belongs to us.
We don't even belong to each other.
Stop the cab.
What do you think?
This ought to be the right kind of place for a tough guy like you.
Garbage cans, rats galore.
Scram.
I said take off.
Beat it.
Let's go.
Driver.
Pull over here.
You know what's wrong with you, Miss whoever you are?
You're chicken.
You've got no guts.
You're afraid to stick out your chin and say, OK, life's a fact.
People do fall in love.
People do belong to each other, because that's the only chance anybody's got for real happiness.
You call yourself a free spirit, a wild thing, and you're terrified somebody's going to stick you in a cage.
Well, baby, you're already in that cage.
You built it yourself.
And it's not bounded in the west by Tulip, Texas, or in the east by Somaliland.
It's wherever you go.
Because no matter where you run, you just end up running into yourself.
Here, I've been carrying this thing around for months.
I don't want it anymore.